

# **SOUVIK DAS**

Communication address: B 80 ,Desai Nagar . Tarsali, Vadodara . Gujarat : 390009

Cell: +91-8160781546 /9547027946

Email ID: <a href="mailto:souvikinox15@gmail.com">souvikinox15@gmail.com</a>

LinkedIn: https://www.linkedin.com/in/souvik-das-14aa8b1b6

#### **PROFESSIONAL SUMMARY:**

Currently work as a Production Engineer at Indutch Composite Pvt. Ltd with more than 5 years of experience in Manufacturing domain. Work in renewable energy sector in rotor blade and Mould manufacturing unit. Also having experience in material management and procurement process. Most of time spend on shop floor to supervise all production activities. also take special care on workmen training and Kaizen activities.

#### PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE:

# Indutch Composite Technology pvt. Ltd (July 2020 to present):

- Take Care of all shop floor production activities and collection of day to day basis data on Material consumption for each project and compare with BOM, calculate manhour, extra manhour (if needed) for each project.
- Creating & filling microplanning for each project, delay analysis.
- Carrying experience in Mould & product manufacturing for wind, automotive & others industries. Also having experience in wind industry related composite & metal equipment manufacturing.
- Creating BOM for Projects and also involved in Material procurement activities, from creating PR to communicated with vendors.
- Also work alongside with Quality control, Process control and Design department to Improvement and troubleshooting of problems.
- Team member of organization dream projects like manufacturing of wind turbine Rotor Blade Mould of length 77.8mtr for Nordex (It's the 1<sup>st</sup> Indian Company making such lengthy Mould), also part of the team manufacturing rotor blades (include prototyping) at Reliance Composite ltd. Who are manufacturing wind turbine blade for 1<sup>st</sup> time.

### Siemens Gamesa Renewable Energy (January 2020 to June 2020):

- Execute the design, analysis, or evaluation of assigned projects using sound engineering principles and adhering to business standards.
- To train, educate the work mans & keep records when they deputed for new job or when any new person is deputed on job.

- Planning of activities and giving explanation of on technical issues.
- Collect every day's material consumption Data for each project.
- To monitor & analyze the reason for rejection / wastage / rework & to initiate corrective action for same the same.
- To meet the target of reduction of WIP at all stages & productivity target as defined & set by superior.
- To carry on additional jobs as & when assigned by the superiors.

# Inox wind ltd. (December 2015 to January 2020)

- Review new processes, received molds/related equipment, and received documentation.
- To get sleeve inspection done on shift basis & maintain records.
- Implement best manufacturing practice like Kaizen, 5S activities in shop floor.
- To work towards achievement in targeted manpower as per sanctioned.
- Oversight & management of front-line manufacturing employees.
- Daily verification & recording of parameters as defined in the relevant process check sheet.
- To verify that equipment's condition is OK & applied poke-yoke on m/c's are effective.
- To improve shop floor work culture, housekeeping during the shifts
- To ensure that safe working condition in entire shop through periodic check on working of safety
- controls. Also, to ensure that applicable PPE is being used by all employees. Create awareness among all employees towards safety culture.
- To execute production plan as per planning.

To plan availability of equipment & manpower to achieve the targeted production.

#### **PROFESSIONAL SKILL:**

- Good hands on experience on Microsoft excel, Microsoft word, Microsoft PowerPoint
- Knowledge on CAD software i.e. Auto CAD, Solid works
- ERP Software: SAP (PP module)

## **EDUCATIONAL QUALIFICATION:**

- 2015 B.Tech in Mechanical Engineering (West Bengal University of technology): 7.16(CGPA)
- 2011 Higher secondary (West Bengal Council of higher secondary education): 65.5 %
- 2009 Secondary (West Bengal Board of secondary education.): 70%

#### **PERSONAL DETAILS:**

- Date of Birth: 08th March 1993
- Language Known: English, Hindi, Bengali,